<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<pg-comp map="Germany">
  <overview>
    Each player represents a power company, which works to supply electricity to cities.
    During the game, each player buys power plants at auction, buys resources to produce
    electricity in those power plants, and builds a network of cities to supply with
    electricity from his power plants. In the end, the player who supplies the most cities
    with power wins the game.
  </overview>

  <limits players="2">
    <regions>3</regions>
    <max-plants>4</max-plants>
    <remove-cards>8</remove-cards>
    <step-2>10</step-2>
    <end-game>21</end-game>
  </limits>

  <limits players="3">
    <regions>3</regions>
    <max-plants>3</max-plants>
    <remove-cards>8</remove-cards>
    <step-2>7</step-2>
    <end-game>17</end-game>
  </limits>

  <limits players="4">
    <regions>4</regions>
    <max-plants>3</max-plants>
    <remove-cards>4</remove-cards>
    <step-2>7</step-2>
    <end-game>17</end-game>
  </limits>

  <limits players="5">
    <regions>5</regions>
    <max-plants>3</max-plants>
    <remove-cards>0</remove-cards>
    <step-2>7</step-2>
    <end-game>15</end-game>
  </limits>

  <limits players="6">
    <regions>6</regions>
    <max-plants>3</max-plants>
    <remove-cards>0</remove-cards>
    <step-2>6</step-2>
    <end-game>14</end-game>
  </limits>

  <preparation>
    Place 3 coal on spaces 1 to 8; 3 oil on spaces 3 to 8; and 3 garbage on spaces 7 and 8;
    1 uranium on each of the spaces 14 and 16.
  </preparation>

  <preparation>
    Take the power plant cards numbered 03 to 10 and place them near the board in two rows.
    In the upper row, place 03 to 06 in ascending order (actual market); in the lower row,
    place power plants numbered 07 to 10 in ascending order (future market). Keep market in
    ascending order as plants are added.
  </preparation>

  <preparation>
    Remove the »Step 3« card and plant number 13 from the card deck, shuffle the remaining
    power plant cards, and place them face down (plant supply). Place the »Step 3« card
    face down under the stack and plant number 13 face down on top of the stack.
  </preparation>

  <notes step="1">
    Every city can have only one house. The building cost for the first house is 10 Elektro.
  </notes>

  <notes step="2">
    At the start of step 2, remove ONCE the lowest numbered power plant from the game and
    replace it with a new one from the draw stack, rearranging the market as always.
  </notes>

  <notes step="2">
    Two players can have houses in each city. The building price for the second connection
    is 15 Elektro.
  </notes>

  <notes step="2">
    If the »Step 3« card is drawn in phase 2 (Auction Power Plants), treat the card as the
    highest power plant and place it at the end of the future market. Immediately shuffle
    the draw stack with the remaining power plants (the power plants that were placed under
    the draw stack during steps 1 and 2 of the game), and place it face down next to the
    game board. Continue the auction of power plants and draw replacements as necessary
    until all players have their chance to buy a new power plant or pass. After finishing
    phase 2, remove the lowest numbered power plant and the »Step 3« card from the market
    and do not draw replacements! Step 3 starts in phase 3.
  </notes>

  <notes step="2">
    If the »Step 3« card is drawn in phase 4 (Building) for replacements of too small power
    plants, remove this card and the smallest numbered power plant from the game and do not
    draw replacements. Shuffle the draw stack with the remaining power plants and place it
    face down next to the game board. Step 3 starts in phase 5.
  </notes>

  <notes step="2">
    If the »Step 3« card is drawn in phase 5 (Bureaucracy), remove this card and the lowest
    numbered power plant from the game and do not draw replacements. Shuffle the draw stack
    with the remaining power plants and place it face down next to the game board. Use the
    re-supply of resources for Step 2 a final time. Step 3 starts in phase 1 of the next
    turn.
  </notes>

  <notes step="3">
    During step 3, there are only 6 power plants in the power plant market and all of these
    power plants are in the actual market and are available to be auctioned.
  </notes>

  <notes step="3">
    Every city can have three houses. The building price for the third house is 20 Elektro.
  </notes>

  <notes step="3">
    In phase 5, remove the smallest numbered power plant from the game and draw a
    replacement from the draw stack. During the last rounds of the game, it is possible
    that the draw stack becomes exhausted. The game continues and in each phase 5, the
    players remove the smallest numbered power plant. It is possible to run out of power
    plants if this goes on for several rounds.
  </notes>

  <notes>
    In the first round of the game, each player must buy a power plant.  Players
    re-determine the player order after auctioning the power plants (after phase 2).
  </notes>

  <notes>
    If no power plant is sold in a round, the players remove the lowest numbered power
    plant from the market, placing it back in the box, and replace it by drawing a power
    plant from the draw stack. They then rearrange the market according to the rules.
  </notes>

  <notes>
    If, at any time during the game, there is a power plant in the actual market with a
    number equal to or lower than the number of cities any player has, it is immediately
    removed from the game and replaced with a new card from the draw stack.
  </notes>

  <turn-order>
    <turn>Determine player order</turn>
    <turn order="std">Buy power plant</turn>
    <turn order="rev">Buy raw materials</turn>
    <turn order="rev">Build cities</turn>
    <turn order="std">Bureaucracy</turn>
  </turn-order>

  <restock players="2" step="1">
    <coal>3</coal><oil>2</oil><trash>1</trash><nuke>1</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="2" step="2">
    <coal>4</coal><oil>2</oil><trash>2</trash><nuke>1</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="2" step="3">
    <coal>3</coal><oil>4</oil><trash>3</trash><nuke>1</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="3" step="1">
    <coal>4</coal><oil>2</oil><trash>1</trash><nuke>1</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="3" step="2">
    <coal>5</coal><oil>3</oil><trash>2</trash><nuke>1</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="3" step="3">
    <coal>3</coal><oil>4</oil><trash>3</trash><nuke>1</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="4" step="1">
    <coal>5</coal><oil>3</oil><trash>2</trash><nuke>1</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="4" step="2">
    <coal>6</coal><oil>4</oil><trash>3</trash><nuke>2</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="4" step="3">
    <coal>4</coal><oil>5</oil><trash>4</trash><nuke>2</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="5" step="1">
    <coal>5</coal><oil>4</oil><trash>3</trash><nuke>2</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="5" step="2">
    <coal>7</coal><oil>5</oil><trash>3</trash><nuke>3</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="5" step="3">
    <coal>5</coal><oil>6</oil><trash>5</trash><nuke>2</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="6" step="1">
    <coal>7</coal><oil>5</oil><trash>3</trash><nuke>2</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="6" step="2">
    <coal>9</coal><oil>6</oil><trash>5</trash><nuke>3</nuke>
  </restock>

  <restock players="6" step="3">
    <coal>6</coal><oil>7</oil><trash>6</trash><nuke>3</nuke>
  </restock>
</pg-comp>
